that keeps the protocol whole
保持协议的完整性
because someone's always gonna push the button
因为总会有人按下按钮
because you get paid to do that.
因为你这样做是有报酬的。
And this is one of those little aha moments
这是那些顿悟时刻之一
of building on top of Ethereum
建立在以太坊之上
is how you build something that runs
是你构建运行的东西的方式
even when you walk away.
即使当你走开时。
I was talking about the walk away test earlier.
我之前谈到了离开测试。
You want to be able to deploy something
您希望能够部署一些东西
and be able to walk away.
并且能够走开。
And it's almost like a two-sided market
这几乎就像一个双向市场
where people can coordinate
人们可以协调的地方
and they can do all the things
他们可以做所有的事情
and everything is automatic
一切都是自动的
and you never have to touch anything.
而且你永远不需要碰任何东西。
And that's the beauty of building
这就是建筑的魅力
a perfectly decentralized system
一个完全去中心化的系统
and building on top of Ethereum.
并建立在以太坊之上。
And you can learn all of these concepts
你可以学习所有这些概念
by going to speedrunetherium.com.
访问 speedrunetherium.com。
And there's a little QR code there to check that out.
那里有一个小二维码可以检查。
Okay, so let me even show you,
好吧，让我给你展示一下，
let's jump over to,
让我们跳到，
so there's ETH skills, right?
所以有 ETH 技能，对吗？
All those concepts, really cool.
所有这些概念，真的很酷。
You just click that and it copies it
你只需点击它，它就会复制它
and you paste it and you give it to your agent.
然后你粘贴它并将其交给你的代理人。
But let's look at speedrunetherium real quick.
但让我们快速了解一下 speedrunetherium。
So there's all of these different lessons.
所以就有了所有这些不同的教训。
And what's really cool is this is AI driven.
真正酷的是这是人工智能驱动的。
So if we wanted to go to this crowdfunding one,
所以如果我们想参加这个众筹活动
I have it right here,
我这里就有，
you can download it locally and then you run it
你可以下载到本地然后运行
and you basically just say slash start
你基本上只是说斜线开始
and you get this little tutor.
然后你就得到了这个小导师。
You have this AI tutor that takes you through things.
这位人工智能导师将带您完成所有事情。
And you can say like, keep going, keep building.
你可以说，继续前进，继续建设。
And it's basically telling me
它基本上告诉我
that it wants to do this certain thing
它想做这件事
and I tell it to keep going.
我告诉它继续前进。
And now it's gonna go back
现在它会回去
and start writing my smart contract for me.
并开始为我编写智能合约。
So it's sitting here writing my smart contracts for me.
所以它坐在这里为我编写智能合约。
And I have a little tutor
我还有一个小导师
that's going to even ask me questions.
那甚至会问我问题。
I can ask my tutor questions.
我可以向我的导师提问。
And then you have a nice UI to interface with your app.
然后你就有了一个漂亮的用户界面来与你的应用程序交互。
So you have this working smart contract app
这样你就有了这个可以运行的智能合约应用程序
with a front end and a smart contract.
具有前端和智能合约。
And then you have an AI tutor
然后你就有了一位人工智能导师
that's teaching you through the things.
那就是通过这些事情来教导你。
Okay, let's wrap it up.
好吧，让我们总结一下。
Speedrun Ethereum is there.
Speedrun 以太坊就在那里。
So for the human, you use speedrunetherium.com.
因此，对于人类来说，您可以使用 speedrunetherium.com。
For your AI agent, you use ethskills.com.
对于您的 AI 代理，您可以使用 ethskills.com。
Those are the two important links
这是两个重要的环节
that I wanna make sure I share.
我想确保我分享。
Okay, so in a multi-agent future,
好的，所以在多智能体的未来，
I think this is coming, right?
我想这即将到来，对吗？
Imagine a whole company of agents talking.
想象一下整个公司的特工在说话。
Agents are gonna need to be able to trust each other.
代理需要能够相互信任。
One agent that's a generalized agent
一个代理是广义代理
will maybe need to hire a specialized agent
可能需要聘请专门的代理人
that does some things like say image generation
可以做一些事情，比如图像生成
or text generation is pretty simple,
或者文本生成非常简单，
but maybe it's a travel agent, right?
但也许是旅行社，对吧？
It's actually someone that books a plan
实际上是有人预订了计划
or books a flight for you.
或为您预订航班。
Maybe there's a flight booking agent
也许有航班预订代理
and your generalized agent would rather pay it
而你的广义代理宁愿支付它
a fraction of a fraction of a cent.
零头零头。
I think agents are going to be hiring each other soon.
我认为代理商很快就会互相雇佣。
And I think what they'll need is some layer
我认为他们需要的是一些层
to pay each other and some layer to trust each other.
互相付出和某些层互相信任。
And that's where ERC 8004 and X402 come in.
这就是 ERC 8004 和 X402 的用武之地。
These are new standards that help agents
这些是帮助代理商的新标准
discover each other, trust each other with reputation
发现彼此，以信誉彼此信任
and pay each other.
并互相付费。
So check out 8004 and X402.
所以看看 8004 和 X402。
Okay, and AI is the new UI.
好的，人工智能就是新的用户界面。
Crypto is hard to use, it's complicated.
加密货币很难使用，而且很复杂。
And sometimes like when you see the call data
有时就像当你看到通话数据时
or a smart contract, it's really nice to think about
或者智能合约，想想真是太好了
you can just talk to an AI agent
你只需与人工智能代理交谈即可
and an AI agent can go make crypto transactions for you.
人工智能代理可以为你进行加密货币交易。
And you should be building apps that allow for this.
您应该构建允许这样做的应用程序。
Aya talked about this real quick.
阿雅很快就谈到了这一点。
While you're building, you should be thinking of crops.
当你建造时，你应该考虑农作物。
You should be building censorship resistant,
你应该建立抗审查制度，
open source, private and secure applications.
开源、私有和安全的应用程序。
Now, a lot of this comes out of the box
现在，很多都是开箱即用的
when you deploy something on Ethereum,
当你在以太坊上部署某些东西时，
but there's a lot more that has to happen.
但还有很多事情要做。
There was a new R skill within ETH skills
ETH技能中有一个新的R技能
that'll help you build ZK circuits to do privacy.
这将帮助您构建 ZK 电路来保护隐私。
Okay, that's it.
好吧，就是这样。
The last thing I wanna leave you with
我想留给你的最后一件事
is that it's never been a worst time in history
这从来都不是历史上最糟糕的时期
to be a junior developer,
成为一名初级开发人员，
but it's never been a better time in history
但这是历史上从未有过的美好时光
to be a solo entrepreneur.
成为一名个体企业家。
And the difference between that is just your mindset.
这之间的区别只是你的心态。
Instead of trying to pad your resume
而不是试图填充你的简历
and get hired as a junior developer,
并被聘为初级开发人员，
go be a solo entrepreneur
成为一名个体企业家
and build things that people wanna use.
并构建人们想要使用的东西。
It's never been easier to take a whole bunch of AI tools
使用一大堆人工智能工具从未如此简单
off the shelf and get product market fit.
下架并获得适合市场的产品。
And you can get product market fit
您可以获得适合市场的产品
and then hire your first developer.
然后雇用你的第一个开发人员。
All right, thank you very much.
好的，非常感谢。
I'm Austin Griffith from the EF.
我是 EF 的奥斯汀·格里菲斯。
I'm at Austin Griffith.
我在奥斯汀格里菲斯。
We've got the QR code there
我们在那里有二维码
for ETH skills for speed run Ethereum.
用于快速运行以太坊的 ETH 技能。
And then there's my Twitter.
然后是我的推特。
I'm Austin at Ethereum.org if you wanna email me
如果你想给我发电子邮件，我是 Ethereum.org 的 Austin
and I'm at Austin Griffith.
我在奥斯汀格里菲斯。
Reach out, my DMs are open.
请联系我，我的私信已开通。
We're always building this cool skill file
我们一直在构建这个很酷的技能文件
and these cool tools to help you learn
这些很酷的工具可以帮助您学习
how to build on Ethereum.
如何在以太坊上构建。
Thank you for having me.
谢谢你有我。
Go build something awesome on Ethereum.
去以太坊上构建一些很棒的东西吧。
Thank you, Austin.
谢谢你，奥斯汀。
Thank you so much.
太感谢了。
Thank you.
谢谢。
We have now reached the final speech of chapter one.
现在我们已经到了第一章的最后演讲部分。
Ethereum as infrastructure for deep self sovereignty
以太坊作为深度自我主权的基础设施
by Shreem Shinder,
作者：施里姆·辛德尔，
team lead of academic secretariat at Ethereum Foundation.
以太坊基金会学术秘书处团队负责人。
Please welcome Shreem.
请欢迎施里姆。
Thank you so much everyone for coming down today
非常感谢大家今天的到来
and for having me to give this talk.
以及让我做这次演讲。
So today I'm going to talk about two things.
那么今天我要讲两件事。
The first thing is that Ethereum is probably
首先，以太坊可能是
history's first very serious attempt
历史上第一次非常严肃的尝试
at actually building infrastructures
在实际建设基础设施时
that can allow for deep and complete self sovereignty.
这可以实现深度和完全的自我主权。
And I'm also gonna talk about how researchers
我还将谈论研究人员如何
and everyone in this room in fact
事实上这个房间里的每个人
has a very critical role to play
发挥着非常关键的作用
in order to ensure that we succeed in this attempt.
以确保我们这次尝试取得成功。
So let me first talk about the context
那么我先谈谈背景
or rather the problem that motivated a lot of things
或者更确切地说，这个问题激发了很多事情
that we see today in the Ethereum space.
我们今天在以太坊领域看到的。
A problem that many scholars had spent years
许多学者花了多年时间解决的问题
and almost their entire careers trying to solve.
几乎他们的整个职业生涯都在试图解决这个问题。
The problem of how can humans effectively coordinate
人类如何有效协调的问题
without explicitly trusting the system
没有明确信任系统
that they used for coordination.
他们用于协调。
So there have been a lot of very serious scholars
所以出现了很多非常认真的学者
like Ostrom and Hobbes who've spent their entire careers
就像奥斯特罗姆和霍布斯一样，他们度过了整个职业生涯
trying to solve this problem.
试图解决这个问题。
But the unfortunate reality is that
但不幸的现实是
it's not until very recently
直到最近
that a viable solution was found.
找到了可行的解决方案。
And as a result of that,
结果，
a lot of the systems that we see today in the world
我们今天在世界上看到的很多系统
actually build around this problem
实际上是围绕这个问题构建的
rather than trying to solve this problem heads on.
而不是试图直接解决这个问题。
Which is why we see that a lot of the systems
这就是为什么我们看到很多系统
that we deal with in today's world
我们在当今世界所面对的
actually has what is called a back door.
实际上有所谓的后门。
So for example, if you look at systems like banking systems,
举例来说，如果你看看银行系统这样的系统，
it's very easy for the centralized authorities
对于中央政府来说这很容易
to freeze your account.
冻结您的帐户。
If you look at platforms, whether it's social media platforms
If you look at platforms, whether it's social media platforms
or whether it's gaming platforms,
或者无论是游戏平台，
it's very easy in the name of violation
以违规的名义很容易
of an arbitrary set of rules of conduct.
一套任意的行为规则。
It's very easy for people to get deplatformed
人们很容易失去平台
without possibly serious reasons for it.
没有可能有严重的原因。
And now with the advent of AI,
现在随着人工智能的出现，
we have a whole new set of back doors,
我们有一套全新的后门，
which is the models that we use
这是我们使用的模型
or we heavily depend on today.
或者我们严重依赖今天。
They can very arbitrarily be withdrawn.
它们可以非常任意地撤回。
Their API can be shut down
他们的API可以关闭
and their rates could be locked down,
他们的利率可能会被锁定，
meaning that no new training happens.
这意味着不会发生新的训练。
And all of this just goes to say that
所有这一切都说明了
back doors structurally exist in most systems around us.
后门在结构上存在于我们周围的大多数系统中。
Now, I don't want to talk about what would happen
现在我不想谈论会发生什么
if they are exercised,
如果他们得到锻炼，
because that is often considered an edge case
因为这通常被认为是一种边缘情况
and those really vary from scenario to scenario.
这些确实因场景而异。
But I'd like to make the point that the very fact
但我想指出的是事实
that they exist itself shapes behavior of its users.
它们的存在本身就决定了用户的行为。
And this is a very important point
这是非常重要的一点
because it's not about whether they get exercised,
因为这不是他们是否锻炼的问题
but it's about whether they structurally actually exist.
但这是关于它们在结构上是否确实存在。
So people can preemptively self-censor
这样人们就可以先发制人地进行自我审查
under the fear of getting deplatformed.
由于担心被取消平台。
People can preemptively not build things
人们可以先发制人地不建造东西
that actually need to be built.
实际需要建造的。
And in very extreme cases,
并且在非常极端的情况下，
they can even try to circumvent some of these systems,
他们甚至可以尝试绕过其中一些系统，
which ends up causing more harm than it does good.
这最终造成的弊大于利。
So that's the fundamental reality
这就是基本的现实
that structural dependencies actually shape user behavior,
结构依赖性实际上塑造了用户行为，
which brings us to think about the question of,
这让我们思考这个问题，
okay, is it possible for this back door
好的，这个后门可以吗
to not exist by construction?
不通过建设而存在？
Is it possible?
是否可以？
And what would happen in a scenario
以及在某个场景中会发生什么
where there is no back door?
哪里有没有后门？
And I think cryptography was the first serious tool.
我认为密码学是第一个严肃的工具。
And using it for the first time,
并且是第一次使用，
you could actually build technical primitives
你实际上可以构建技术原语
to help humans coordinate,
帮助人类协调，
where arbitrary revocability is not just an edge case,
其中任意可撤销性不仅仅是一种边缘情况，
or it's not just an unlikely scenario,
或者这不仅仅是一个不可能发生的情况，
but it's architecturally impossible.
但这在建筑上是不可能的。
And the question was, okay,
问题是，好吧，
now that we have these beautiful tools,
现在我们有了这些漂亮的工具
is it possible to make these programmable?
是否有可能使这些可编程？
Is it possible to make these composable?
是否可以使这些可组合？
And is it possible to make it available
是否有可能使其可用
at a large scale for everyone?
大规模地为每个人服务？
And that's kind of where Ethereum comes into play.
这就是以太坊发挥作用的地方。
And then that's, in many sense,
然后，从很多意义上来说，
a lot of the motivations behind why Ethereum exists
以太坊存在背后的很多动机
and why a lot of the applications
以及为什么很多应用程序
that are built on top of Ethereum exist.
建立在以太坊之上的存在。
So Ethereum's claim is very precise, right?
所以以太坊的说法非常准确，对吗？
It's programmable in the sense that
从某种意义上说它是可编程的
any rule can be specified and can be enforced
任何规则都可以指定并可以执行
without a trusted third party.
没有可信赖的第三方。
It's composable in the sense that it guarantees stack.
它是可组合的，因为它保证了堆栈。
And I'm gonna talk about this a little more
我会再多谈谈这个
in the next few slides,
在接下来的几张幻灯片中，
but also it's available at scale,
而且它还可以大规模使用，
which means that anyone, anywhere,
这意味着任何人、任何地方、
without permission from any platform,
未经任何平台许可，
can actually take part in the system.
可以实际参与系统。
And each of these properties has, in the past,
这些属性中的每一个在过去都具有
been attempted in some shape or form,
已尝试以某种形式或形式，
but it's almost for the first time
但这几乎是第一次
that all these three guarantees can be achieved
这三个保证都能实现
at this very same time.
就在此时。
And that's kind of Ethereum's claim.
这就是以太坊的主张。
But the truth is, it actually doesn't end
但事实是，它实际上并没有结束
at the protocol layer.
在协议层。
So in Aya's talk, she had briefly touched upon
所以在阿雅的演讲中，她简短地谈到了
how there are very important decisions
如何做出非常重要的决定
and important constraints and trade-offs to be considered
以及需要考虑的重要限制和权衡
while designing the protocol layer.
while designing the protocol layer.
But the harsh reality is that, given that every,
但残酷的现实是，考虑到每一个，
like given that the system is composable
就像系统是可组合的一样
and every piece of stack just goes one on top of the other,
每一块堆栈都只是一个叠在另一个之上，
even if the protocol is built
即使协议已构建
keeping all these properties in mind,
牢记所有这些属性，
anywhere in the stack,
堆栈中的任何位置，
if that notion of self-sovereignty is broken,
如果自我主权的观念被打破
then it never reaches the user.
那么它就永远不会到达用户手中。
So even at the consensus layer, execution layer,
所以即使在共识层、执行层，
or, very importantly, the application layer,
或者，非常重要的是，应用层，
if things break down,
如果事情破裂，
these guarantees that we want to give to the final user
我们希望向最终用户提供这些保证
can never actually reach the final user.
永远无法真正到达最终用户。
So just to make it a little more concrete,
所以为了让它更具体一点，
here are some very concrete examples or scenarios
这是一些非常具体的例子或场景
where these aspirations could actually break down.
这些愿望实际上可能会破灭。
So if you look at RPC concentration,
所以如果你看看 RPC 浓度，
in a scenario where there are only two to three providers
在只有两到三个提供商的情况下
which stand between most users and the protocol,
它位于大多数用户和协议之间，
coordinated censorship by these handful of providers
这些少数提供商的协调审查
can very easily guarantee,
可以很容易地保证，
the base layer guarantees obsolete.
基础层保证过时。
If you look at block builder concentration,
如果你看看区块建造者的浓度，
if in a theoretical scenario,
如果在理论场景中，
the MEV supply chains are actually produced
MEV供应链实际生产
by only a handful of dominated builders,
仅由少数占主导地位的建筑商，
and these builders start to collude with each other
这些建设者开始相互勾结
and start to coordinate with each other,
并开始相互协调，
then transaction ordering
然后是交易排序
almost becomes commercially permissioned.
几乎获得商业许可。
And if you look at AI agent infrastructure,
如果你看看人工智能代理基础设施，
what if the proprietary interface endpoints
如果专有接口端点怎么办
managing on-chain assets become a centralized choke point?
管理链上资产成为中心化瓶颈？
This essentially causes a choke point
这本质上会造成一个瓶颈
at a very sensitive layer,
在非常敏感的层，
like the layer that actually makes decisions
就像实际做出决策的层一样
on behalf of the user.
代表用户。
So the promise of composability
所以可组合性的承诺
is that trustlessness stacks upward,
不信任是向上叠加的，
and it also introduces a risk
这也带来了风险
that a single non-trustless component
单个非信任组件
can break the guarantee for the whole stack.
可能会破坏整个堆栈的保证。
So that's the context,
这就是上下文，
and now I'm gonna talk a little bit about
现在我要谈谈
what it means for your work
这对你的工作意味着什么
and what are the ways in which
以及有哪些方式
research can engage more deeply with these problems
研究可以更深入地解决这些问题
to ensure that this guarantee
以确保这一保证
goes all the way up to the end user.
一直到最终用户。
So I often like to talk
所以我经常喜欢说话
in the language of academic disciplines
用学科语言
because a lot of the audience that I like to engage with
因为我喜欢与很多观众互动
are serious researchers.
是认真的研究人员。
So here are some ways that your expertise
因此，这里有一些方法可以发挥您的专业知识
is genuinely needed to solve this problem
确实需要解决这个问题
and to ensure that these guarantees go all the way on top.
并确保这些保证始终发挥作用。
So for mechanism designers,
所以对于机制设计者来说，
it's almost fundamental that
这几乎是基本的
without the right incentive structures,
如果没有正确的激励结构，
these coordination mechanisms fail,
这些协调机制失效了，
and people will immediately turn back
人们会立即回头
to centralized intermediaries.
到中心化的中介机构。
Cryptographers are more direct
密码学家更直接
because privacy and proof aggregation
因为隐私和证据聚合
are still open problems,
仍然是悬而未决的问题，
and this critical research is what will ensure
这项重要的研究将确保
that the protocol's promises are actually keepable.
该协议的承诺实际上是可以兑现的。
For AI researchers and AI builders in this room,
对于在座的人工智能研究人员和人工智能构建者来说，
trustless infrastructure with an opaque model
具有不透明模型的去信任基础设施
isn't trustless, and this is a very big opportunity
不是无需信任的，这是一个非常大的机会
and a very big open problem
和一个非常大的开放问题
that's actually waiting for a solution.
这实际上是在等待解决方案。
If you're a legal scholar or governance scholar,
如果您是法律学者或治理学者，
on-chain governance, jurisdiction,
链上治理、管辖权、
independent enforcement, and doubt design,
独立执行，质疑设计，
all of them need actual people
他们都需要真实的人
who understand legal frameworks,
了解法律框架的人，
people who understand how power works,
了解权力如何运作的人，
and not just merely how code works.
而不仅仅是代码如何工作。
And similarly, for political economists,
同样，对于政治经济学家来说，
looking at how decentralized systems avoid capture,
看看去中心化系统如何避免捕获，
how you can actually sustain public goods,
如何真正维持公共产品，
which are the backbone of a lot of the applications
这是许多应用程序的支柱
and a lot of things that are built in the space,
还有很多在这个空间里建造的东西，
and how can you actually sustain them,
以及你如何才能真正维持它们，
and how do you prevent power concentration.
以及如何防止权力集中。
These are all important political economy questions
这些都是重要的政治经济学问题
that is waiting for your expertise.
那正在等待您的专业知识。
And similarly, when you look at science
同样，当你看科学时
and knowledge studies, there are a lot of questions
还有知识学习，有很多问题
around open access, provenance, and credentialing,
围绕开放获取、出处和认证，
and this is what makes this infrastructure
这就是这个基础设施的原因
actually trustless.
实际上是不信任的。
And this is a very structural solution
这是一个非常结构化的解决方案
or structural dependencies on which
或结构依赖
this technical infrastructure relies on.
这个技术基础设施依赖。
And one more thing that I want to mention here
我还想在这里提到一件事
is that open source is often thought of
是人们经常想到的开源
as just a filing requirement,
仅作为备案要求，
or open source is often thought of
或者经常想到开源
as just like an afterthought.
就像事后的想法一样。
But the truth is, even if you have...
但事实是，即使你有...